4 times the action. 4 times the adventure. 4 times the fantastic.
Fantastic Four is a action, fantasy, science fiction film directed by Tim Story.
During a space voyage, four scientists are altered by cosmic rays: Reed Richards gains the ability to stretch his body; Sue
Storm can become invisible; Johnny Storm controls fire; and Ben Grimm is turned into a super-strong … thing.
Together, these "Fantastic Four" must now thwart the evil plans of Dr.
Doom and save the world from certain destruction.
Reed Richards / Mr. Fantastic, played by Ioan Gruffudd.
Sue Storm / Invisible Woman, played by Jessica Alba.
Johnny Storm / Human Torch, played by Chris Evans.
Ben Grimm / The Thing, played by Michael Chiklis.
Victor von Doom / Doctor Doom, played by Julian McMahon.
Leonard, played by Hamish Linklater.
Fantastic Four (sometimes stylized as Fantastic 4) is a 2005 superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics superhero team created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby.
It was directed by Tim Story and written by Mark Frost and Michael France.
The film stars Ioan Gruffudd, Jessica Alba, Chris Evans, Michael
Chiklis, Julian McMahon, and Kerry Washington.
The film follows the origins of the titular team as they learn to come to terms with
their newfound abilities following their exposure to cosmic rays.
This was the second live-action Fantastic Four film to be filmed.
A previous attempt, titled The Fantastic Four, was a B movie
produced by Roger Corman that ultimately went unreleased.
Fantastic Four was released in the United States on July 8, 2005.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics (though Evans and Chiklis's performances
were praised), but has gone through some re-evaluation over the years after its release.
The film grossed $333.5 million worldwide and was a box office success.
A sequel, Fantastic Four: Rise of the Silver Surfer, was released in 2007.
A reboot was released in 2015, while another, set in the Marvel
Cinematic Universe (MCU), was released in 2025.
Evans, who would portray Captain America in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU), later reprised
his role as Johnny Storm / Human Torch in the MCU film Deadpool & Wolverine (2024).
The film explores themes of mask, friendship, marriage
proposal, fire, sibling relationship.
The tone is thought_provoking.